Guide to the Samplified Digital Recording Studios Records
University of Houston Libraries
Samplified Digital Recording Studios Records
1995-2003
06/2012-006
Samplified Digital Recording Studios (Houston, Tex.)
8.60 linear feet
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
This collection contains Alesis Digital Audio Tapes (ADATs), invoices, photographs, and posters from Samplified Digital Recording Studios and is divided into four series: Recordings, Invoices, Promotional Materials, and Photographs.
Historical Note:
Engineer Keenan “Maestro” Mosley, born in 1958 and originally from Philadelphia, opened his Samplified Digital Recording Studios in Missouri City around 1990. There he recorded artists such as DJ Screw, K-Rino, Point Blank, BAM, the Terrorists, Klondike Kat, Big 50, and many others. National recording artists such as Run-DMC, Ice T, Master P, and Spice 1 also stopped into Samplified Studios to record while they were performing in Houston. Samplified Digital Recording Studios was in business for over a decade, until it stopped getting clients around 2003. Mosley, who went by the professional name Keenan Lyles, died in 2010 at the age of fifty-two. He was survived by his son Kendall Mosley, who raps as Chane.
Access Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
Samplified Digital Recording Studios (Houston, Tex.)
Genre/Form of Material:
Digital Audio Tapes; Invoices; Photographs; Posters
Personal Name:
DJ Screw, 1971-2000
Topical Term:
Hip-hop -- Texas -- Houston; Rap (Music) -- Texas -- Houston; Rap musicians -- Texas -- Houston
Accruals:
Additional materials were acquired from Kendall Mosley on 06/27/2012 and 10/8/2012.
Conditions Governing Access:
Open for research.
Acquisition Information
Information of acquisition method not available.
Physical Characteristics or Technical Requirements:
Due to the fragility of the original ADATs, they cannot be played directly. Digital copies of the individual audio tracks can be accessed in the Special Collections Reading Room by advance request. These materials may require up to one week to access. Contact Julie Grob (jgrob@uh.edu").
Scope and Contents
This collection contains Alesis Digital Audio Tapes (ADATs), invoices, photographs, and posters from Samplified Digital Recording Studios and is divided into four series: Recordings, Invoices, Promotional Materials, and Photographs. The ADATs contain recordings by many prominent Houston hip hop artists, mostly notably several sets of tapes containing master recordings by DJ Screw. Due to the fragility of the original ADATs, they cannot be played directly, but digital access files are available.
Detailed List of Contents
- Recordings
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains 190 Alesis Digital Audio Tapes, or ADATs, recorded at Samplified Studios. ADAT is a magnetic tape format used for the simultaneous digital recording of eight analogue audio or digital audio tracks at once. ADATs became very popular among recording studios in the 1990s due to their high quality and affordability. The tapes in this series contain recordings by many prominent Houston hip hop artists, mostly notably several sets of tapes containing master recordings by DJ Screw. The tapes are arranged alphabetically by artist, and titles were taken directly from the tapes. Due to the fragility of the original ADATs, they cannot be played directly. Digital copies of the individual audio tracks can be accessed in the Special Collections Reading Room by advance request. These materials may require up to one week to access. Contact Julie Grob (jgrob@uh.edu) for more information.
  - 20-2-Life – A, undated (Box 1, Item 1)
  - 20-2-Life – B, undated (Box 1, Item 2)
  - 20-2-Life – Tape 1, undated (Box 1, Item 3)
  - 20-2-Life – Tape 2, undated (Box 1, Item 4)
  - 20-2-Life – Tape 3, undated (Box 1, Item 5)
  - 20-2-Life – Tape 4, undated (Box 1, Item 6)
  - 20-2-Life – 1, undated (Box 1, Item 7)
  - 20-2-Life – 2, undated (Box 1, Item 8)
  - 20-2-Life, undated (Box 1, Item 9)
  - 20-2-Life, undated (Box 1, Item 10)
  - 20-2-Life song vocal additional tracks, undated (Box 1, Item 11)
  - 20-2-Life song additional tracks, undated (Box 1, Item 12)
  - 20-2-Life radio vocals, undated (Box 1, Item 13)
  - 20-2-Life radio vocals – 4, undated (Box 1, Item 14)
  - 20-2-Life watch in vocals, 97 (Box 1, Item 15)
  - 20-2-Life radio versions II – 1, undated (Box 2, Item 1)
  - 20-2-Life – 1, undated (Box 2, Item 2)
  - 20-2-Life – 2, undated (Box 2, Item 3)
  - 20-2-Life – 3, undated (Box 2, Item 4)
  - 20-2-Life – 1, 1997 (Box 2, Item 5)
  - 20-2-Life – 2, 1997 (Box 2, Item 6)
  - 20-2-Life – 3, 1997 (Box 2, Item 7)
  - 20-2-Life – 4, 1997 (Box 2, Item 8)
  - 20-2-Life II – 1, undated (Box 2, Item 9)
  - 20-2-Life II – 2, undated (Box 2, Item 10)
  - 20-2-Life II – 3, undated (Box 2, Item 11)
  - 20-2-Life II – 4, undated (Box 2, Item 12)
  - 20-2-Life Black – A, undated (Box 2, Item 13)
  - 20-2-Life Black – B, undated (Box 3, Item 1)
  - 20-2-Life Black – C, undated (Box 3, Item 2)
  - 55 – Believe in Yourself/Innate Set #2, Track 3, undated (Box 3, Item 3)
  - 55 – Believe in Yourself/Innate Set #2, Track 4, undated (Box 3, Item 4)
  - AC Chill, undated (Box 3, Item 5)
  - AC Chill, undated (Box 3, Item 6)
  - After Life Les – Former B-50 Project, HAWK vocals, undated (Box 3, Item 7)
  - BAM – 1, undated (Box 3, Item 8)
  - BAM – 2, undated (Box 3, Item 9)
  - BAM – 3, undated (Box 3, Item 10)
  - BAM, Set Two – 1, undated (Box 3, Item 11)
  - BAM, Set Two – 2, undated (Box 3, Item 12)
  - BAM, Set Two – 3, undated (Box 3, Item 13)
  - BAM for Icy and KB tracks – 3, undated (Box 3, Item 14)
  - Big 50 – 4, undated (Box 3, Item 15)
  - Big 50, 1-8, undated (Box 4, Item 1)
  - Big 50, 9-16, undated (Box 4, Item 2)
  - Big 50, 17-24, undated (Box 4, Item 3)
  - Big 50 Set One, 2, undated (Box 4, Item 4)
  - Big 50 Set One, 3, undated (Box 4, Item 5)
  - Big 50 Set One, 4, undated (Box 4, Item 6)
  - Big 50 Set #2, 9-16, undated (Box 4, Item 7)
  - DJ Screw, 1-8, undated (Box 4, Item 8)
  - DJ Screw, 9-16, undated (Box 4, Item 9)
  - DJ Screw – Screw Part 1 Side 2, 1-8, undated (Box 4, Item 10)
  - DJ Screw – Screw Part 1 Side 2, 9-16, undated (Box 4, Item 11)
  - DJ Screw – Part #2, Side One, 1-8, undated (Box 4, Item 12)
  - DJ Screw – Part #2, Side One, 9-16, undated (Box 4, Item 13)
  - DJ Screw – Part #2, Side One, 17-24, undated (Box 4, Item 14)
  - DJ Screw – Big Tyme Screw Mix Side One, 1-8, undated (Box 4, Item 15)
  - DJ Screw – Big Tyme Screw Mix Side One, 9-16, undated (Box 5, Item 1)
  - DJ Screw – Big Tyme Screw Mix Side Two, 1-8, undated (Box 5, Item 2)
  - DJ Screw – Big Tyme Screw Mix Side Two, 9-16, undated (Box 5, Item 3)
  - DJ Screw – Part 2, Side 2: Vocals for Git High wit da blankster, 1-8, undated (Box 5, Item 4)
  - DJ Screw – Part 2, Side 2: High wit Blanksta, 9-16, undated (Box 5, Item 5)
  - DJ Screw – Big Tyme Radio Vocals Get high with blank, 1-8, undated (Box 5, Item 6)
  - DJ Screw – Big Tyme Get high with blank, 25-32, undated (Box 5, Item 7)
  - DJ Screw – Vol 2 – Big Tyme Da Music Radio, undated (Box 5, Item 8)
  - G-Rap [G-Rapp the General] – Beat Box Set # one, 1, undated (Box 5, Item 9)
  - G-Rap [G-Rapp the General] – Beat Box Set # one, 2, undated (Box 5, Item 10)
  - G-Rap [G-Rapp the General] – Beat Box Set # one, 3, undated (Box 5, Item 11)
  - G-Rap [G-Rapp the General] – Beat Box Set # one, 4, undated (Box 5, Item 12)
  - G-Rap [G-Rapp the General] – Beat Box Set two, 1, undated (Box 5, Item 13)
  - G-Rap [G-Rapp the General] – Beat Box Set two, 2, undated (Box 5, Item 14)
  - G-Rap [G-Rapp the General] – Beat Box Set two, 3, undated (Box 5, Item 15)
  - G-Rap [G-Rapp the General] – Beat Box Set two, 4, undated (Box 6, Item 1)
  - Innate – Set #2, B, undated (Box 6, Item 2)
  - Innate – Set #2, C, undated (Box 6, Item 3)
  - Innate – Set #3, B, undated (Box 6, Item 4)
  - Innate – Set #3, C, undated (Box 6, Item 5)
  - Innate – Set #3, D, undated (Box 6, Item 6)
  - Innate – Set #4, A, undated (Box 6, Item 7)
  - Innate – Set #4, B, undated (Box 6, Item 8)
  - Innate – Set #4, C, undated (Box 6, Item 9)
  - Innate – Set #4, D, undated (Box 6, Item 10)
  - Innate – Set #5, 1, undated (Box 6, Item 11)
  - Innate – Set #5, 2, undated (Box 6, Item 12)
  - Innate – Set #5, 3, undated (Box 6, Item 13)
  - Innate – Set #5, 4, undated (Box 6, Item 14)
  - Innate – Set #7, 1, undated (Box 6, Item 15)
  - Innate – Set #7, 2, undated (Box 7, Item 1)
  - Innate – Set #7, 3, undated (Box 7, Item 2)
  - Innate – Set #7, 4, undated (Box 7, Item 3)
  - Innate – Set #8, 1, undated (Box 7, Item 4)
  - Innate – Set #8, 3, undated (Box 7, Item 5)
  - Innate – Set #8, 4, undated (Box 7, Item 6)
  - Innate – Set #9, 1, undated (Box 7, Item 7)
  - Innate – Set #9, 2, undated (Box 7, Item 8)
  - Innate – Set #9, 4, undated (Box 7, Item 9)
  - Innate – Set #10, undated (Box 7, Item 10)
  - Innate – Radio, 1, undated (Box 7, Item 11)
  - Innate – Radio, 3, undated (Box 7, Item 12)
  - Innate, undated (Box 7, Item 13)
  - Innate, undated (Box 7, Item 14)
  - Innate – Street Murder #12, 4, undated (Box 8, Item 1)
  - Kamikazi, Mix Tape Set 1, 1, 2003 (Box 8, Item 2)
  - Kamikazi, Mix Tape Set 1, 2, 2003 (Box 8, Item 3)
  - Kamikazi, Mix Tape Set 2, undated (Box 8, Item 4)
  - Kamikazi, Mix Tape Set 2, undated (Box 8, Item 5)
  - Kamakaze – They don't want to see us ball, 1-8, undated (Box 8, Item 6)
  - Kamakaze – don't want to see us ball, 1-8, undated (Box 8, Item 7)
  - Kamakaze – don't want to see us ball, 17-24, undated (Box 8, Item 8)
  - [Klondike] Kat – Set #, 1, undated (Box 8, Item 9)
  - [Klondike] Kat Kat – Set #, 2, undated (Box 8, Item 10)
  - [Klondike] Kat Kat – Set #, 3, undated (Box 8, Item 11)
  - [Klondike] Kat Kat – Set #, 4, undated (Box 8, Item 12)
  - [Klondike] Kat, 1-8, undated (Box 8, Item 13)
  - [Klondike] Kat, 9-16, undated (Box 8, Item 14)
  - [Klondike] Kat, 17-24, undated (Box 8, Item 15)
  - [Klondike] Kat – Set #2, 25-32, undated (Box 9, Item 1)
  - [Klondike] Kat, 1, 1998 (Box 9, Item 2)
  - [Klondike] Kat, 2, 1998 (Box 9, Item 3)
  - [Klondike] Kat, 3, 1998 (Box 9, Item 4)
  - [Klondike] Kat, 4, 1998 (Box 9, Item 5)
  - Klondike Kat – 96 Mix, 1, undated (Box 9, Item 6)
  - Klondike Kat – 96 Mix, 2, undated (Box 9, Item 7)
  - Klondike Kat – 96 Mix, 3, undated (Box 9, Item 8)
  - Klondike Kat – 96 Mix, 4, undated (Box 9, Item 9)
  - Klondike Kat, 1, undated (Box 9, Item 10)
  - Klondike Kat, 2, undated (Box 9, Item 11)
  - Klondike Kat, 3, undated (Box 9, Item 12)
  - Klondike Kat, 4, undated (Box 9, Item 13)
  - Klondike Kat – 2nd Set, 1-8, undated (Box 9, Item 14)
  - Klondike Kat – 2nd Set, 9-16, undated (Box 9, Item 15)
  - Klondike Kat – 2nd Set, 17-24, undated (Box 10, Item 1)
  - [Klondike] Kat – #40 Ghetto Baby, 25-32, undated (Box 10, Item 2)
  - [Klondike] Kat, undated (Box 10, Item 3)
  - [Klondike] Kat, undated (Box 10, Item 4)
  - Klondike Kat – The Lyrical Lion, A, undated (Box 10, Item 5)
  - Klondike Kat – The Lyrical Lion, B, undated (Box 10, Item 6)
  - LEZ [Lex Moné?], 1, undated (Box 10, Item 7)
  - LEZ [Lex Moné?], 2, undated (Box 10, Item 8)
  - LEZ [Lex Moné?], 3, undated (Box 10, Item 9)
  - LEZ [Lex Moné?], 4, undated (Box 10, Item 10)
  - LEZ [Lex Moné?] – Set #2 music tracks, undated (Box 10, Item 11)
  - LEZ [Lex Moné?] – Set #2 Use this tape for 24 track song with Jhymie, ESG, undated (Box 10, Item 12)
  - LEZ [Lex Moné?] – Set #2 music tracks Use this tape for 24 track song with ESG as tape #2, undated (Box 10, Item 13)
  - LifeStyl – Set #2, 1, undated (Box 10, Item 14)
  - LifeStyl – Set #2, 2, undated (Box 10, Item 15)
  - LifeStyl – Set #2, 3, undated (Box 11, Item 1)
  - LifeStyl – Set #2, 4, undated (Box 11, Item 2)
  - LifeStyl – Set #3, 1, undated (Box 11, Item 3)
  - LifeStyl – Set #3, 2, undated (Box 11, Item 4)
  - LifeStyl – Set #3, 3, undated (Box 11, Item 5)
  - LifeStyl – Set #3, 4, undated (Box 11, Item 6)
  - LifeStyl – Set #1 Vocals, undated (Box 11, Item 7)
  - LifeStyl, 9-16, undated (Box 11, Item 8)
  - LifeStyl, 17-24, undated (Box 11, Item 9)
  - Mynd Over Matter – Part 2, 3, 1997 (Box 11, Item 10)
  - Mynd Over Matter – Part 2, 4, 1997 (Box 11, Item 11)
  - Mynd Over Matter, 3, undated (Box 11, Item 12)
  - Point Blank, A, undated (Box 11, Item 13)
  - Point Blank, B, undated (Box 11, Item 14)
  - Point Blank – #29, A, undated (Box 11, Item 15)
  - Point Blank – #29, B, undated (Box 12, Item 1)
  - Point Blank – #31, B, undated (Box 12, Item 2)
  - R.J. [Richard Johnson] – Beatbox, 1, undated (Box 12, Item 3)
  - R.J. [Richard Johnson] – Beatbox, 2, undated (Box 12, Item 4)
  - R.J. [Richard Johnson] – Beatbox, 3, undated (Box 12, Item 5)
  - R.J. [Richard Johnson] – Beatbox, 4, undated (Box 12, Item 6)
  - R.J. [Richard Johnson] – Set #2, 1, undated (Box 12, Item 7)
  - R.J. [Richard Johnson] – Set #2, 2, undated (Box 12, Item 8)
  - R.J. [Richard Johnson] – Set #2, 3, undated (Box 12, Item 9)
  - R.J. [Richard Johnson] – Set #2, 4, undated (Box 12, Item 10)
  - R.J. [Richard Johnson] – Song Dump/Reel, 1, undated (Box 12, Item 11)
  - R.J. [Richard Johnson] – Song Dump/Reel, 2, undated (Box 12, Item 12)
  - R.J. [Richard Johnson] – Song Dump/Reel, 3, undated (Box 12, Item 13)
  - R.J. [Richard Johnson] – KB Icy [Icey Hott] tracks, 1, undated (Box 12, Item 14)
  - R.J. [Richard Johnson] – KB Icy [Icey Hott] tracks, 2, undated (Box 12, Item 15)
  - Tech 9 – Lyrical – CAP, 1, undated (Box 13, Item 1)
  - Tech 9 – Lyrical – CAP, 2, undated (Box 13, Item 2)
  - Tech 9 – Lyrical – CAP, 3, undated (Box 13, Item 3)
  - Tech 9 – Lyrical – CAP, 4, undated (Box 13, Item 4)
  - Wreckless Klan, 1, undated (Box 13, Item 5)
  - Wreckless Klan, 2, undated (Box 13, Item 6)
  - Wreckless Klan, 3, undated (Box 13, Item 7)
  - Wreckless Klan, 4, undated (Box 13, Item 8)
  - Wreckless Klan II, 1, undated (Box 13, Item 9)
  - Wreckless Klan II, 2, undated (Box 13, Item 10)
  - Wreckless Klan II, 3, undated (Box 13, Item 11)
  - Wreckless Klan II, 4, undated (Box 13, Item 12)
  - Wreckless Klan – Remixed vocals, undated (Box 13, Item 13)
- Invoices
  This series contains invoices created by Samplified Digital Recording Studios between 1995 and 1997. Invoices have been left in their original order within the folder.
  - Invoices, 1995 – 1997 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Promotional Materials
  The Promotional material series is divided into two sub-series by format; Posters and Promo Cards.
  - Posters
    The Posters sub-series is arranged alphabetically by the artist or label; most folders contain one to four posters. Most of these posters hung on the walls at Samplified Digital Recording Studios, and many are signed by the artists.
    - 2-Def, undated (Ovs box 1, Folder 1)
    - .380, undated (Ovs box 1, Folder 2)
    - Big 50, 1997 (Ovs box 1, Folder 3)
    - Coop MC, undated (Ovs box 1, Folder 4)
    - Game Don’t Lie, undated (Ovs box 1, Folder 5)
    - G-low, undated (Ovs box 1, Folder 6)
    - Guerilla Maab, 1999 (Ovs box 1, Folder 7)
    - Innate Sound Recordings, undated (Ovs box 1, Folder 8)
    - Inmate Records, undated (Ovs box 1, Folder 9)
    - I-Witness, undated (Ovs box 1, Folder 10)
    - Kamakazeez, undated (Ovs box 1, Folder 11)
    - Killa Klan, undated (Ovs box 1, Folder 12)
    - Klondike Kat, 1993, 1996 (Ovs box 1, Folder 13)
    - LifeStyl, 1997 (Ovs box 1, Folder 14)
    - MSP, undated (Ovs box 1, Folder 15)
    - Oddiscee, 1999 (Ovs box 1, Folder 16)
    - On Da Grind Records, undated (Ovs box 1, Folder 17)
    - Point Blank, undated (Ovs box 1, Folder 18)
    - PSK-13, 1998 – 1999, undated (Ovs box 1, Folder 19)
    - Soul Fruit, undated (Ovs box 1, Folder 20)
    - Southern Funk Playas, 1995 (Ovs box 1, Folder 21)
    - South Park Danger Zone, undated (Ovs box 1, Folder 22)
    - South Park Mexican, undated (Ovs box 1, Folder 23)
    - Trinity Garden, undated (Ovs box 1, Folder 24)
    - True 2 Life Players, undated (Ovs box 1, Folder 25)
    - World Wide Riders, undated (Ovs box 1, Folder 26)
    - Wreckless Khan, undated (Ovs box 1, Folder 27)
    - 20-2-Life, undated (Drawer F.3, Ovs folder 4)
    - Icey Hott, undated (Drawer F.3, Ovs folder 5)
    - The Terrorists, undated (Drawer F.3, Ovs folder 6)
  - Promo Cards
    - Promo Cards, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Photographs
  This series is divided into two sub-series: Personal Photographs and Promotional Photographs. The personal photographs sub-series contains photos taken at the studio, and the promotional photographs sub-series contains signed promotional photographs from artists given to the studio.
  - Personal Photographs
    - Personal photographs, undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Promotional Photographs
    - Promotional photographs, undated (Box 14, Folder 4)